Welcome to this video about this exercise
task about statically modeling operations
in constructing terms.
This task is referring to the lecture where
there were defined operations for vectors
graphics.
Just as a reminder.
This was what was the slides of the lecture
with different operations that are defined.
And these graph operations, now extended by
another operation.
And these operations should be for polygons.
And the operation should be capable of trying
(?graphs) which are like this one here.
So, now we have to figure out what we require
in order to draw a polygon which looks roughly
like this.
And this is a regular polygon.
So, we have to think about what defines a
regular polygon.
And when we think about this, then we can’t
really think about polygons.
Also, we have this example here.
And we can’t think about what would be required
to (?cross) at the polygon.
First of all, I think we can think about the
edges.
Or the corners of this cross.
We know how many edges there must be.
Because we have a polygon with size “N”.
Some “N”.
So, the smallest polygon would be of 3 edges.
And then, we could have one for 4 edges which
would be square and then it continues.
And we look at this one, this has for instance
7 edges and yeah.
It is a regular polygon.
So, one pyramid should be for the number of
edges.
And the other one, well, I think it is quite
obvious.
Because of this (?crate) here is showing how
large this polygon is in the examples.
The other one shows somehow defines these
sides of the polygon.
And when we look at these graphics.
We can roughly say, well, it hasn’t extent
from mines two to two of the “Y” axis
on the “X” axis.
It is roughly the same.
And when you think about how to play all these
corners of the polygon.
We can think about placing them in a circle.
So, we can think of defining the polygons
by the radios of the middle point of the polygon.
And thinking about this, we can define this
type here.
So, we have to define the type of the polygons
and- yeah, we are defining the type for polygons,
that’s our task.
And we have one parameter which is for the
extent of the (?graph) and this should of
course be some- well, which can also be in
the middle of 0.5 or something like this.
So, this should be a “float”.
And the other parameter should be the number
of edges or corners of the polygon.
We can say this is an “Int” value.
The resulting type is of course “Picture”.
So, when we apply the polygon function, we
want to have a picture.
So, now replace this type of definition here,
so this describes the type of polygon function.
And now we can continue with the second part
of the task.
Now, this part is about giving a picture.
And we have nearly cleared the operation now.
Which is the polygon function.
We don’t need to know how exactly it is
(?rust) the polygon but we know that it takes
all the numbers of the corners.
And the size of the polygon.
And then it is calculated and you– (?graphic
a) polygon as a picture.
And we can use this in order to define how
we get this picture roughly.
So, we do not think about rotation of the
polygon.
That is not really necessary.
That was written in the first class already.
So, it is not necessary to think about the
direction of corners.
So, we could rotate it in order to get two
different positions.
But it is about how it is.
How we could get such a polygon if they were
a function which depicted the edges somehow.
Now when we think about how to use our operation.
We can also think about how- to define types
for the polygon.
So, we were thinking about what is required
to define a polygon.
And now, we just simply must fill what is
missing for our polygons here.
So, when we define this picture here, then
we need two polygons.
Because these are two polygons of course.
One is above and one is below here.
So, somehow, we need two polygons.
And these polygons require the parameters
we defined before.
So, we have to think about the size and as
we said before, could be the radios that define
that size.
So- the size here the radios are 2.
So, the polygon is 2 and in this case for
the bigger polygon and then, we have of course
to count the edges of the polygon.
So, when we count here, we get 13 edges.
So, the first polygon.
And the second polygon that’s the one above.
We can also define a size here.
When we look at this picture, we could say,
well, it is roughly.
Besides one- yeah, that should be the radios
about roughly that we get for this polygon.
And then we also have to count here.
So, it is 7 edges and well, that is not done
yet.
Because we have to- when we tried like this,
we would have 2 polygons above each other.
To get the picture here we have to somehow-
move the polygons correctly.
Well, the first polygon is at the center of
the graph.
If we think we can place the polygon by placing
the origin of the radios, which I think is
a good assumption here.
So, we could say, we don’t have to move
the first polygon.
But we have to move the second polygon.
And there, we can use the translated function.
So, we can say, translated and then- we- yeah.
We
define the polygon as the first parameter.
And the required the second and third parameters
to move the polygon.
And there we can say, well, we don’t want
the “x” axis, but we want to move on the
“y” axis.
And if we want to move the origin, we need
to get to this point.
So, we have to move it 3 up.
And when we do this, we get this as a result
of using a polygon function in order to get
this picture here.
And then, we are done with this task.